<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>python on S. Sharma&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://sshawarma.github.io/tags/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in python on S. Sharma&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 22:44:50 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sshawarma.github.io/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Reddit Upvote Predictor Part 1</title>
      <link>https://sshawarma.github.io/posts/2020/12/reddit-upvote-predictor-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 22:44:50 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sshawarma.github.io/posts/2020/12/reddit-upvote-predictor-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Hey there.
I wanted to start working more with Tensorflow, so I decided to do a simple project where I try to predict the number of upvotes a given Reddit post will receive in a certain amount of time.
This project is very suitable for machine learning, since the number of upvotes $y$ that a post gets can be predicted using a linear equation, of the form $\sum_{i=1}^n w_ix_i+b_i$ where $w_i$ and $b_i$ can be calculated through a method such as gradient descent and $x_i$ is the feature in particular.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plotting Reddit Comment Trends With Pandas</title>
      <link>https://sshawarma.github.io/posts/2020/09/plotting-reddit-comment-trends-with-pandas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 20:29:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sshawarma.github.io/posts/2020/09/plotting-reddit-comment-trends-with-pandas/</guid>
      <description>Hey there!
I wanted to learn more about Pandas, a Python library for data analysis, so I decided to embark on a mini-project to experiment with it. If you use Reddit, you&amp;rsquo;ve probably seen a chain of comments like below:
Clearly, you can see that there&amp;rsquo;s a pattern in the number of upvotes. Every reply to the parent comment receives less upvotes compared to the previous reply. It would be interesting to create a bar graph, comparing the number of upvotes the parent comment received, the number of upvotes the first reply received, the number of upvotes the second reply received, &amp;hellip;, the number of upvotes the nth reply received.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
