<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>S. Sharma&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://gh0std3v.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on S. Sharma&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 22:03:37 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gh0std3v.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Privating Repos</title>
      <link>https://gh0std3v.github.io/posts/2021/01/privating-repos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 22:03:37 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gh0std3v.github.io/posts/2021/01/privating-repos/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I went ahead and private some of my repositories, including repositories of projects that I&amp;rsquo;m currently working on. I just wanted to quickly explain why I&amp;rsquo;m doing this.
I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted to hold myself accountable for the projects I do. Sometimes, when I do a project, I can become uninterested in what I&amp;rsquo;m doing or I&amp;rsquo;ll hold off on it due to other responsibilities. As a result, this leaves me with plenty of repositories, some of which are completed projects and others that are not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Interesting Fact About Logarithms</title>
      <link>https://gh0std3v.github.io/posts/2021/01/an-interesting-fact-about-logarithms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 18:46:08 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gh0std3v.github.io/posts/2021/01/an-interesting-fact-about-logarithms/</guid>
      <description>Today I learned something interesting about logarithms. Namely, that:
$$\lg x \approx \ln x + \log x$$
with less than 1% error!
The &amp;ldquo;proof&amp;rdquo; behind this is as follows:
$$\frac{\ln x + \log x}{\lg x} = \frac{\frac{\lg x}{\lg e} + \frac{\lg x}{\lg 10}}{\lg x}$$
$$= \frac{(\lg e + \lg 10)(\lg x)}{\lg x \lg 10 \lg e}$$
$$= \frac{1}{\lg e} + \frac{1}{\lg 10}$$
$$ = \ln 2+ \log 2 $$
The above is approximately equivalent to $0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy New Years</title>
      <link>https://gh0std3v.github.io/posts/2021/01/happy-new-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 20:10:49 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gh0std3v.github.io/posts/2021/01/happy-new-years/</guid>
      <description>Hey there.
It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I&amp;rsquo;ve last written. Hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to write more this year. That&amp;rsquo;s it. Tomorrow, I plan on making a post. Happy new years! :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reddit Upvote Predictor Part 1</title>
      <link>https://gh0std3v.github.io/posts/2020/12/reddit-upvote-predictor-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 22:44:50 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gh0std3v.github.io/posts/2020/12/reddit-upvote-predictor-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Hey there.
I wanted to start working more with Tensorflow, so I decided to do a simple project where I try to predict the number of upvotes a given Reddit post will receive in a certain amount of time.
This project is very suitable for machine learning, since the number of upvotes $y$ that a post gets can be predicted using a linear equation, of the form $\sum_{i=1}^n w_ix_i+b_i$ where $w_i$ and $b_i$ can be calculated through a method such as gradient descent and $x_i$ is the feature in particular.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Update Again</title>
      <link>https://gh0std3v.github.io/posts/2020/12/quick-update-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 22:03:29 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gh0std3v.github.io/posts/2020/12/quick-update-again/</guid>
      <description>Hey there.
I haven&amp;rsquo;t been writing recently because I got busy with school/work and felt too tired to write anything. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping that this week I can start writing everyday again.
:)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting a MAC Address on a Mac</title>
      <link>https://gh0std3v.github.io/posts/2020/11/getting-a-mac-address-on-a-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 20:33:28 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gh0std3v.github.io/posts/2020/11/getting-a-mac-address-on-a-mac/</guid>
      <description>Hey there.
Recently, I needed to write some code in C to get the MAC address of a particular interface. On Linux, this is pretty easy to do. However, on BSD systems and, more importantly, on macOS, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t as straightforward and I had to do some digging to find an answer.
On Linux, generally I would find the MAC address by doing an ioctl() call with the argument SIOCGIFHWADDR like so:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unfinished Projects</title>
      <link>https://gh0std3v.github.io/posts/2020/11/unfinished-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 22:06:43 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gh0std3v.github.io/posts/2020/11/unfinished-projects/</guid>
      <description>Hey there.
I dropped writing for a little bit just to give myself a break and give myself some time to work on my project. Speaking of projects, this year I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to cultivate more persistence. I feel like in the past I would start a project, go somewhat far with it, and then fail to follow through and provide something that worked the way I wanted.
More critically, I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel satisfied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Rust</title>
      <link>https://gh0std3v.github.io/posts/2020/11/learning-rust/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 20:47:48 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gh0std3v.github.io/posts/2020/11/learning-rust/</guid>
      <description>Hey there.
I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to write yesterday because I was working on my project. In other news, I decided to learn a little bit of Rust through the Official Rust Book since I used to play around with the C programming language. So far, I&amp;rsquo;ve found Rust to be an interesting language that remedies some of the problems with &amp;ldquo;unsafe&amp;rdquo; languages like C while still attempting to give access to the low level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Watson Time Tracker</title>
      <link>https://gh0std3v.github.io/posts/2020/11/watson-time-tracker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 22:06:05 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gh0std3v.github.io/posts/2020/11/watson-time-tracker/</guid>
      <description>I was working on my project today and I decided to try out a tool that I&amp;rsquo;ve been interested in using for a long time. Watson is a time management tracker that you can use to track how much time you spend on your projects. Today, according to Watson, I spent 1 hour and 11 minutes working on my project.
I hope to use it more to track my time and hopefully in the future I can talk about the benefits/cons of using something like Watson.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wikipedia Graph Update</title>
      <link>https://gh0std3v.github.io/posts/2020/11/wikipedia-graph-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 21:47:51 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gh0std3v.github.io/posts/2020/11/wikipedia-graph-update/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to give a quick update on the project that I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on. Today, I managed to render the nodes and links on the canvas and I think I also have a better understanding of D3.js than before. Of course, I think some optimizations can be made and it can be made more graphically appealing (labels on the nodes and drag/pan/zoom are two features that I definitely want to implement soon).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
